Did you sell out Uvo?
Answer me!
[thunder crashing]
[Nobunaga] I'll take that as a yes.
Move!
Now, hold on a minute.
Let's hear what he has to say.
Are you kidding?
What's there to say?
Just calm down, alright?
Remember what the boss said.
There are ways we can avoid the events
that are predicted in the fortune.
Hisoka, explain to us
what happened this week.
[Hisoka] I cannot.
Huh?
Sorry, but all that I can tell you
is that the first poem was accurate.
Nothing more, I'm afraid.
-Do you hear that? Move!
-Wait. Not just yet.
Hisoka, why can't you explain?
Because telling you would amount
to saying what I cannot.
So, I say nothing.
But it's not that I won't tell,
it's that I can't say more
than I already have.
If you won't accept that answer,
then for the sake of defending myself...
I have no other choice but to fight.
[theme music playing]
ALLIES x AND x LIES
[narrator] After seeing his fortune,
Nobunaga suspects Hisoka
has betrayed them,
and draws his sword.
[scoffs] Forget it.
You're way too much of a pain to fight.
Yeah right! Like that would stop me!
[gasps]
[Chrollo] Nobunaga.
-Be quiet a moment.
-Huh?
-Did the boss just do that?
-Probably.
Hisoka, I have some questions for you.
Answer them if you can.
In the fortune, tell me,
what does "secrets" mean?
[Hisoka] The Troupe members' powers.
[Chrollo] How many of them?
Seven. No, excuse me, eight.
You and Uvogin, Shizuku, Machi, Franklin,
Pakunoda, Shalnark and I make eight.
Hmm. You only learned
of Kortopi's ability yesterday?
[Hisoka] That's correct.
-What's the chain-user's ability?
-Can't say.
-Can you say what he looks like?
-I cannot.
And what is your relationship to him?
I can't tell you.
I understand.
BANDIT'S SECRET
The red-eyed customer is the chain user,
who possesses no fewer than two abilities.
The one that he used to capture Uvogin,
and the other is one
that restricts Hisoka's actions.
The "sword of law," the phrase mentioned
in the second poem of the fortune
forces a person to obey a set of rules.
Such as "don't lie to me."
Or "do not reveal anything about me."
Something of that nature.
And it would also stand to reason
that he planted something
that's inside of Hisoka's body.
[chuckles]
The poem starts by mentioning
a trade of sorts,
but the second half just describes
what the customer took.
And this would seem to suggest
that the sword of law
was used to attack Hisoka.
In other words, Hisoka was forced
to betray us against his will.
[Hisoka] Oh, so good.
If the sword can curb Hisoka's speech,
it must be quite powerful indeed.
[Hisoka] Yes, I knew you were brilliant.
I'm definitely going to enjoy...
killing you.
Now, let's all review what we know.
First off, the enemy uses chains.
A Manipulator would be using
actual physical chains in battle.
If he's a Conjurer, then he took down Uvo
by using Nen chains.
So is there a difference
between those two?
[Shalnark] Yes, a big one.
A Conjurer can appear to be empty-handed.
That's a huge advantage.
I see.
Conjurers have to do lots
of visual training,
but once they have, they can make
their weapons appear at will.
But our real problem at the moment
is what's restricting Hisoka.
[Franklin] A sword of law must involve
rules he has to follow.
[Shalnark] Yes, he's probably forced
to follow the orders Chrollo talked about.
He's likely barred
from attacking the chain user, as well.
And he would probably die
if he broke his promise.
[Hisoka chuckling] How fun.
There's no sword of law
anywhere in my body.
That fortune was my own creation.
I only revealed the abilities
of two members, not eight.
It was a risky gamble, one that would
have turned the entire Troupe against me
had the boss not figured that out.
All this to keep the spiders
in Yorknew City,
so I can fight the boss.
If they were to leave now,
there's no telling when I'd see him again.
But then what is Hisoka's second poem
supposed to mean?
It says "The 11-legged spider
longs for home.
Five more legs shall break
before it's done.
But from your shelter do not roam,
for of those five, you shall be one."
Our hideout. That's the temporary shelter.
If Hisoka leaves here, he'll die.
What about the longing for home?
It means that we're homesick.
[Shalnark] But if we do go back home,
then half of us won't survive.
Okay, I get it.
Uvo, Hisoka, Shizuku, Pakunoda
and Shalnark.
One more makes half the members.
Did the fortune predict any other deaths?
It has to be Feitan, Kortopi or me.
We didn't have all the data we needed
to get our fortunes told.
I'm staying right here for the time being.
There are things that I still wish to do
before I die.
I won't be leaving our shelter.
Well, boss, what now?
[Phinks] Leave or stay?
[Chrollo] Let's stay.
[Killua] No way.
Wait, but why not? You were the one
who wanted to go and capture
the Phantom Troupe in the first place.
Yeah, well that was back when it wouldn't
have been pointless.
But why is it pointless?
'Cause there's no reward money anymore,
so you would be taking
a huge risk for absolutely nothing.
Maybe so, but it'd be worth it to finally
capture the Phantom Troupe, wouldn't it?
You really need to take a hard look
at your priorities.
Do you even remember why we're here?
Well, do you?
-For Greed Island.
-Exactly!
The Southern Piece auction
starts in two days,
so we need to make a whole lot
of money before then.
Actually, I have a great idea
about how we can get the game.
You've got a plan, fill me in.
Hmm. It's a secret right now!
[groaning] Stop being such a little tease
and spit it out!
I can't breathe! You're gonna kill me!
Anyway, I'll figure out something
for the game, but for now,
we should keep trailing the Troupe.
Do you really have a plan
to get Greed Island?
Yeah, but it isn't guaranteed to work
or anything.
Well, okay then, how likely is it to work?
Like, what's the probability of success?
Uh, maybe 70 percent.
-Seventy?
-I mean, maybe more like 60.
[Killua] So, it's probably 50-50.
But still, I guess that’s a lot better
than trying to earn six billion Jenny
in two days.
[Killua] Okay, fine.
I'll let you be in charge of Greed Island,
but it'd be stupid to try to deal
with the Troupe on our own.
We'll need Kurapika's help.
We can't do this without him.
Hmm.
[Melody] Where are you off to, boss?
I'm going shopping.
I told you that earlier, didn't I?
[Melody] Basho and I will accompany you.
You okay here, Squala?
No problem.
[Squala] That was close!
[Melody]
Guard those Scarlet Eyes well, alright?
Sure. As long as these guys are here,
I should be fine.
[dogs whining]
[Melody] Okay, I'm off.
[Squala] Yeah, I'll see you later.
[footsteps approaching]
How did it go?
I couldn't get a straight answer.
I asked the community for any updates
regarding the auction today, but no luck.
You should go back there and tell them
the Troupe is still alive!
That ought to make them
change their minds.
I'm afraid that still
won't change anything.
The Mafia wants to avoid any friction
with Meteor City.
I think it's safe to assume that their war
on the Phantom Troupe is over.
Really?
But that wasn't the information
I was hoping to find.
My only real concern is whether
the auction will proceed as planned.
Are you thinking of intercepting them?
That's insane!
How do you think you're gonna do that
without the Mafia's help, huh?
You have it all wrong, Leorio.
I'm not counting on the Mafia.
Far from it.
[gasps]
[Gon]
Hey, Kurapika, let us help you, okay?
We'll do anything.
Just tell us what you need.
[Killua] Come on, say no.
-But the reward was rescinded.
-[Gon] I know.
I still want to stop the Troupe.
I haven't changed my mind about that.
[Killua] Turn him down.
Turn him down!
You'd be risking your lives.
[Killua]
Great. Throw a little fuel on the fire.
Right. Then let's discuss it.
Okay.
[Killua] He agreed?
First, we're gonna need someone
to watch their base
and to provide updates.
Yeah, I can do that.
[Kurapika] We only want the woman
called Pakunoda.
-You can ignore the others.
-Okay.
Be incredibly careful.
Oh, don't worry. I won't push my luck.
I'm also going to need a driver
to accompany me.
Leorio, can I count on you?
[spluttering] Yeah.
It'll be fine.
You'll be totally safe
if you're with Kurapika.
[Leorio] Oh, knock it off, Killua.
You're making it sound like I'm terrified
or something, and I'm totally not!
Okay, what about me?
[Kurapika] Create a diversion
that will draw their focus.
Hey, wait a minute!
That job sounds way too dangerous.
You really expect Gon
to face the Troupe members again?
[Kurapika] Depends on our strategy.
I'm listening. What kind of strategy?
A simple one, actually.
While the enemy is busy dealing with Gon,
I'll capture Pakunoda
and quietly make my escape.
That plan sounds a little shaky to me.
[Kurapika]
Perhaps, but there are too many variables
to devise anything more concrete.
Now, as for Gon's strategy,
I'll let him decide that.
Just hold their attention
for at least half a second,
a full second if possible.
A full second, if I can?
[Kurapika] Yes.
[Gon]
Keep their attention for a whole second?
Can I do that?
[Kurapika] Gon.
You're the key to this plan.
Can you handle it?
I'm not really sure. I need time to think.
We have six hours.
If the auction proceeds as scheduled...
the spiders will make their move
before then.
Hey, you never let us help you before.
Why start now?
Because the risk I'm taking has grown.
I must eliminate Pakunoda immediately.
No matter the cost.
[Killua gasps] Wow.
[Leorio] So, this is why Kurapika
seems so different.
His resolve's gotten even stronger.
Kurapika.
Could you use your Nen dagger on me?
-[gasps]
-What are you talking about?
Yeah, weren't you listening?
If Kurapika attacks someone who's not
a Spider, he'll die!
Keep your voice down!
Then I don't get it. Kurapika has
a Nen dagger in his chest, doesn't he?
[gasping]
I mean, since he's not a member
of the Phantom Troupe...
What I'm about to say
will make the risk I face even greater.
Okay.
Let's go, Killua.
The answer to your question is yes.
It's possible.
Each of my five chains has a separate
and unique function.
And two of them are to be used
solely against the Spiders.
This one is Chain Jail.
It restrains the target and forces them
into a state of Zetsu.
This is for capturing Spiders.
This one is called Judgment Chain.
I stab the target's heart with this dagger
and declare a binding rule.
Break that rule and you die.
As you're aware, there's a Nen dagger
residing in my own heart, as well.
At first, I planned to use it on myself
on the condition that I would die
if I ever used my chains
against anyone outside the Troupe.
But then I realized
I had missed something.
What if attacking myself meant breaking
the very rule I had set?
[thunder crashing]
It was possible I would be an exception,
but there was no way for me
to know for sure.
So, I adjusted the rule further.
I will only use my Chain Jail
against the Phantom Troupe.
That means I can use Judgment Chain
on anyone I choose.
But that chain has a condition too.
But what kind of condition?
[Kurapika] This chain can only be used
when my eyes are scarlet.
Hey, wait. You can change them yourself?
It took practice.
It was a while before I could turn them
scarlet at will.
I mastered the power in my middle finger
by vowing never to release the chain
and to always risk death.
The one in my little finger was resolved
by my unique nature.
When my eyes turn scarlet
is when I become a Specialist.
And I gain the ability to use
any power I've learned at full strength.
I'm not sure what all that means,
but what about your Nen dagger?
You can use it on me, can't you?
Yes.
Go ahead. Set whatever rule you want.
You're dedicated. I appreciate that.
Just curious. Can you make three
of those daggers?
You can just cancel it, right?
Erase the rule as soon
as the mission's over?
Killua! Leorio!
Killua and I had a little talk.
-And since we're working together...
-[Killua] We should risk together.
[Killua and Leorio] What do you say?
The answer to both is yes.
But all three of you
are making a big mistake.
I want you to know,
I never had any intention
of using my dagger on you guys.
Well, then why did you put yourself
in danger by telling us your secret?
[Kurapika] I wanted to thank you, Gon.
No, I wanted to thank all of you
for your resolve.
And if one of you ends up
revealing my secret, which I doubt,
I still won't regret a thing.
I have been blessed with good friends.
That's not fair, Kurapika.
Because the pressure of risking my life
isn't nearly as bad
as letting down a friend.
That was my goal from the beginning.
Oh, okay! I get it now! [laughing]
[Kurapika chuckling]
[Killua] That is so not funny!
Alright.
Well, I'm heading out.
There's no time to waste.
Be real careful out there, Killua!
Yeah. You just leave it to me.
[thunder rumbling]
[Shizuku] In the chamber
of treasure ill-gotten,
there is no choice but endless sleep.
Your greatest fear should solitude be,
lest upon your lonesome form he creep.
[Pakunoda]
On a day dark and poorly lit,
a simple choice: betrayal or pride.
In a cramped room, you must face it.
For the reaper lingers at your side.
[Shalnark] Even one call do not make.
When needed most, it won't connect.
To answer your phone, another mistake.
One time in three,
the reaper calls collect.
Now, let's split up into groups.
That's how we'll operate
for the next week.
Make absolutely sure you're never alone.
Shizuku, Pakunoda and Machi.
Kortopi, Phinks and Feitan.
Nobunaga and Shalnark are with me.
Bonolenov, Franklin
and Hisoka will stay here.
Hey, boss, just so you know...
Some little kids,
they know about this place.
[Chrollo] Kids?
Well, they don't have anything
to do with the chain user,
but I can't help but be
a little bit worried.
Oh, yeah, I totally forgot!
Hey boss, I think we ought to recruit
these kids.
[Machi] Whoa, hold on. That wasn't
why I mentioned them, Nobunaga.
What do you mean?
[Chrollo] I see.
They do sound rather interesting.
But from what you've told me,
it doesn't sound like they'll join us.
Then we'll change their minds.
It's worth meeting them, at least.
[Machi] No, boss, don't listen to him.
Alright, Machi, what is the source
of your concern?
It's... just a hunch.
A hunch? Your instincts are too reliable
to ignore.
It could be there's something important
about those kids.
Let's make more dummy hideouts
just to be safe.
Kortopi, can you make me ten more?
I can make 50.
And the second anyone enters
one of the fakes, I'll know.
See, my copies act as my En, too.
[Killua] Something's not right.
Am I in the wrong place?
No, that's impossible.
No way!
There weren't this many buildings before!
[thunder crashing]
[narrator] As rain falls, the operation
to capture Pakunoda begins.
[theme music playing]
-[Gon] Coming up, Gon...
-[Killua] And Killua's...
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I'm Gon!
-I'm Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Feitan,
another Troupe member.
His hobby is torture,
which is pretty awesome.
[darkly] And he's interested
in Greed Island too.
That's a pretty terrible impression.
[Gon] Next time:
"Beloved and Beleaguered."
-[Killua] Shepherd.
-[Gon] Woof!
-[Killua] Maltese.
-[Killua] Pomeranian.
-[Gon] Woof!
-[Killua] Gon.
-[Gon] Hi!